southamptonfc.com 2019-12-01

# Privacy Policy | Southampton FC | Southampton FC

## PRIVACY POLICY

### **Southampton FC Privacy Policy**

Southampton Football Club is committed to protecting your personal information. We want to be as transparent as possible about how and why we use your personal information. This privacy policy sets out the way in which your personal information is provided to, and is handled by, Southampton Football Club and other members of St Mary’s Football Group and gives you information about your rights and how you can get in touch with us.

**Who We Are**

Southampton Football Club Limited (company number 53301) is a professional football club who operates in the St Mary’s Football Group (company number 06951765). Its learning and development sister company is St Mary’s Training Centre Limited which operates under the trading name “Saints Learning” (company number 02892833).

St Mary’s Football Group also includes our affiliated charity, Saints Foundation (SFC) (company number 04312794, registered charity number 1090916)

We have a Data Protection Lead, who can be contacted by e-mail on [legal@saintsfc.co.uk](mailto:legal@saintsfc.co.uk) or by post addressed to Data Protection Lead, St Mary’s Stadium, Britannia Road, Southampton SO14 5FP.

**Categories of Personal Information We Collect About You**

To enable you to register an account on the [Southampton FC official website](https://www.southamptonfc.com/), we may collect and use the following personal information about you:

  * your first name and last name
  * your e-mail address
  * your country of residence 
  * your date of birth 
  * your gender
  * information about how you use our website, IT, communication and other systems
  * your responses to surveys, competitions and promotions
  * if you choose to sign in with Facebook, Twitter or Google, we may receive the information listed above from these third party accounts you link to us
  * the IP address, data showing when you visited and information showing which website pages you visited

To enable you to purchase on the [Southampton FC online retail store](http://www.southamptonfc.com/store) or the [Southampton FC ticketing website](https://tickets.saintsfc.co.uk/) in addition to the information listed above, we may collect the following personal information about you:

  * your title 
  * your delivery address
  * your company details (if applicable) 
  * your home, work and mobile telephone number 
  * your billing information, transaction and payment card information
  * your purchase history and saved items
  * information to enable us to undertake credit or other financial checks on you (where you are spreading the cost of your season ticket for example)

We may also collect the following additional information if you come to St Mary’s Stadium or our Training Ground facility as a fan, guest or we host your event:

  * CCTV recordings from when you visit our premises
  * Information about your visit (including date and time of visit)
  * Dietary requirements, disabilities and injuries 

If you interact with Saints Foundation or Saints Learning, for example, by participating in a community project, attending a soccer school programme, enrolling on an apprenticeship scheme or participating in work-place training, we may collect the following personal information about you:

  * the participant’s name, school and year group (where applicable)
  * the participant’s ethnicity and disability information 
  * the participant’s next of kin details (including next of kin name and contact details)
  * the participant’s criminal record information where this has been provided to us either by you or a third-party organisation (such as the police)
  * the participant’s employer’s details 
  * the participants examination results, where such examinations are taken through Saint Learning

**Why do we collect personal information about you?**

  * To ensure the safety of those who enter our premises (including St Mary’s Stadium and our Training Ground facility) and the prevention of crime by keeping a record of who has entered our premises (through ticketing information) and recording and monitoring CCTV within our premises.

  * To enable us to administer any competition or other offers/promotions which you have entered into

  * To request feedback on our products, services and events and to undertake market research

  * To send you marketing materials (excluding e-mails) where we can demonstrate a relationship with you and you have not told us that you do not want to receive these.

  * To maintain a list of people who have asked not to receive direct marketing material from us.

  * To process your job application (if you apply for a job with us)

  * To enhance or improve your experience with us. This may mean that we learn about your preferences and on-line or purchasing habits and then tailor our communications with you to make sure that what we send is relevant to you (‘profiling’).

  * To track your activity on our digital platforms

  * To allow our business processes to function efficiently, for example transacting with our partners, carrying out audits, producing management information and dealing with complaints.

  * To assist with operational and compliance measure such as training

  * To enable a statistical analysis to help us manage our business, e.g. in relation to our financial performance, customer base, product range or other efficiency measures

  * To prevent and detect fraud against you or St Mary’s Football Group

**To comply with our legal obligations**

****This may include complying with law enforcement agencies, court or other governing organisations and to ensure your right are met under the UK Data Protection Act. This can also include statutory compliance reporting including statutory returns and health and safety reporting.

**To comply with our governing body requirement such as the Premier League and the Premier League Charitable Fund**

We may rely on legitimate interest in order to process and share personal information with our governing bodies.

Saints Foundation process this special category personal information under Article 9(2)(D) GDPR as Saints Foundation is pursuing a legitimate activity and is processing special category data which relates to participants who have regular contact with the projects which Saints Foundation run (i.e. the legitimate activity).

**Who do we share your information with?**

We may share your information with the following parties:

| 

Service providers who work for us, including marketing agencies, CRM database providers, reporting systems, website hosts and payment portal providers.

| 

We currently use the following third parties Delete Limited, Two Circles Limited, Advance Ticketing Limited, PCS Technology Ltd, CPOMS Systems Limited, Sports Fusion Limited, AMS Media Group, Substance 2005 Limited, Worldpay LLC, Apple Inc (Apple Pay) and PayPal (Europe) S.a.r.l et Cie S.C.A (PayPal)   
  
---|---|---  
| 

On occasions, to Social media platform providers, where you have an account, in order for us to compare information about you in our database in order to enrich the data we hold about you. 

| 

We currently share this information with Facebook, Twitter, Snapchat and Instagram   
  
| 

With our commercial sponsors. Where you have given your consent, we may contact you in order to tell you about a range of initiatives and offers from our commercial partners.

| 

A current list of our commercial partners is found [here](https://www.southamptonfc.com/saints-partners).  
  
| 

Other members of the St Mary’s Football Group

| 

Please see the “Who we are” section at the start of this privacy policy  
  
| 

Our governing bodies, law enforcement or other regulatory bodies

| 

This may include the Premier League, the Premier League Charitable Fund and the Football Association.  
  
| 

Our credit referencing agencies 

| 

This currently includes Secure Trust Bank Public Limited Company and V12 Retail Finance Limited  
  
| 

Our professional and legal advisors and auditors

| 

This may include external solicitors, our insurers and auditors that we instruct on our behalf from time to time.   
  
We only allow our service providers to handle your personal information if we are satisfied they take appropriate measures to protect your personal information. We also impose contractual obligations on service providers to ensure they can only use your personal information to provide services to us and to you.

We may also need to share some personal information with other parties, such as potential buyers of some or all of our business or during a re-structuring. Usually, information will be anonymised but this may not always be possible. The recipient of the information will be bound by confidentiality obligations. We will never sell your information to anyone. 

**How your personal information is collected**

Most of the personal information that we process is collected directly from you—in person, by telephone, text or email, by completing a participation form **** and/or via our websites. However, we may also collect information from publicly accessible sources, or from a third party including credit reference agencies, customer due diligence providers, our official sponsors and partners and our governing bodies (including the Football Association, Premier League). 

We may also collect personal information from cookies on our website (full details are available in our [cookies policy](https://www.southamptonfc.com/club/cookie-policy)) and  via our IT systems through our door entry systems (such as our turnstiles) and reception logs; and our automated monitoring of our websites and other technical systems, such as our computer networks and connections, CCTV and access control systems, and communications systems.

**Promotional Communications**

We may use your personal information to send you updates by email, text message, telephone or post about our products and/or services, including exclusive offers, promotions or new products and/or services. We have a legitimate interest in processing your personal information for promotional purposes (see above ‘Why do we collect personal information about you?’). This means we do not usually need your consent to send you promotional communications. However, where consent is needed, we will ask for this consent separately and clearly. 

We will always treat your personal information with the utmost respect and never sell it to other organisations outside St Mary’s Football Group Limited for marketing purposes.

_____________________________________________________________________________________________________________

You have the right to opt out of receiving promotional communications at any time by:

  * contacting us at [supporterrelations@saintsfc.co.uk](mailto:supporterrelations@saintsfc.co.uk)
  * using the ‘unsubscribe’ link in emails or asking us to stop texting you in a prescribed manner 
  * updating your marketing preferences by clicking “update preferences” on any email we send you. 

We may ask you to confirm or update your marketing preferences if you instruct us to provide further products and/or services in the future, or if there are changes in the law, regulation, or the structure of our business.

_____________________________________________________________________________________________________________

Where we use your information for the purpose of promotional and marketing purposes, we’ll use your personal information to send you direct marketing and to better identify products and services that interest you. We do that if you are one of our supporters, clients or customers or if you’ve interacted with us another way such as entering a prize promotion, asking to receive e-mails, enquiring into hospitality (whether for a match day or non-match day), competitions or registering your interest by other means.

This means we’ll:

  * create a profile about you to better understand you as a supporter, client or customer and tailor the communications we send you (including our marketing messages) based off of your order history, cookies and online behaviour;
  * tell you about other products and services you might be interested in;
  * recommend better ways to manage what you spend with us, like suggesting a more suitable product based on what you use; and
  * try to identify products and services you’re interested in.

**Children’s personal data**

We are dedicated to the protection of children’s personal information. We recommend that children read this privacy policy with their parents and/or guardians. We endeavour to limit the amount of personal information we collect from individuals who are under the age of 13. Children aged 13 and over have access to our services but may be restricted from age appropriate services and advertising

Individuals who are under 13 must always ask their parent and/or guardian for permission 

  * before you set up an account at <https://southamptonfc.com/>
  * [](https://southamptonfc.com/)before you enter our competitions or prize draws (subject to separate terms and conditions)
  * before you agree to purchase any of our products on-line though any of our websites

**How long your information will be kept and where your personal information is held**

**HOW LONG?** We keep different information for different lengths of time but as a rule we will not keep any information in a form that allows the identification of the person it is about for any longer than we have a reason to have it.

**WHERE?** Information may be held at our offices and those of our third-party agencies, service providers, representatives and agents as described above (see above: ‘Who we share your personal information with’). Some of these third parties may be based outside the European Economic Area. 

**OUTSIDE THE EEA?** To deliver services to you, it is sometimes necessary for us to share your personal information outside the European Economic Area (EEA), e.g.:

  * with our service providers located outside the EEA;
  * if you are based outside the EEA;
  * where there is an international dimension to the services we are providing to you.

These transfers are subject to special rules under European and UK data protection law. If you would like further information please contact us using the details in the ‘How to contact us’ below.

**Your rights**

You have the following rights, which you can exercise free of charge:

**Access**

| 

The right to be provided with a copy of your personal information (the right of access)  
  
---|---  
  
**Rectification**

| 

The right to require us to correct any mistakes in your personal information  
  
**To be forgotten**

| 

The right to require us to delete your personal information—in certain situations  
  
**Restriction of processing**

| 

The right to require us to restrict processing of your personal information—in certain circumstances, e.g. if you contest the accuracy of the data  
  
**Data portability**

| 

The right to receive the personal information you provided to us, in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and/or transmit that data to a third party—in certain situations  
  
**To object**

| 

The right to object:

—at any time to your personal information being processed for direct marketing (including profiling);

—in certain other situations to our continued processing of your personal information, e.g. processing carried out for the purpose of our legitimate interests.  
  
**Not to be subject to automated individual decision-making**

| 

The right not to be subject to a decision based solely on automated processing (i.e. a decision made without human involvement), including profiling, that produces legal effects concerning you or similarly significantly affects you  
  
For further information on each of those rights, including the circumstances in which they apply, please contact us or see the [Guidance from the UK Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) on individuals’ rights under the General Data Protection Regulation](http://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/).

If you would like to exercise any of those rights, please:

  * email, call or write to us - see below: ‘ **How to contact us’** ;
  * let us have enough information to identify you; 
  * let us have proof of your identity and address (a copy of your driving licence or passport and a recent utility or credit card bill); and
  * let us know what right you want to exercise and the information to which your request relates.

**Keeping your personal information secure**

We have appropriate security measures to prevent personal information from being accidentally lost, used or accessed unlawfully. We limit access to your personal information to those who have a genuine business need to access it. Those processing your information will do so only in an authorised manner and are subject to a duty of confidentiality. 

We also have procedures in place to deal with any suspected data security breach. We will notify you and any applicable regulator of a suspected data security breach where we are legally required to do so.

**How to complain**

We hope that we can resolve any query or concern you may raise about our use of your information. 

The [General Data Protection Regulation](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/PDF/?uri=CELEX:32016R0679&from=EN) also gives you right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority, in particular in the European Union (or European Economic Area) state where you work, normally live or where any alleged infringement of data protection laws occurred. The supervisory authority in the UK is the Information Commissioner who may be contacted at [https://ico.org.uk/concerns](http://ico.org.uk/concerns/) or telephone: 0303 123 1113.

**Changes to this privacy policy**

This privacy notice was published on 28 October 2019. 

We may change this privacy notice from time to time - when we do we will inform you via our website at <https://southamptonfc.com/club/privacy-policy>

**How to contact us**

Please contact us and by post or email if you have any questions about this privacy policy or the information, we hold about you.

Our contact details are shown below:

**Our contact details**  
  
---  
  
By Post: Data Protection Lead, St Mary’s Stadium, Britannia Road, Southampton, SO14 5FP

By e-mail: [zosullivan@saintsfc.co.uk](mailto:zosullivan@saintsfc.co.uk)
